<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STAT-5014 Fall 2019</title>
    <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content on STAT-5014 Fall 2019</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector and matrix math</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/25/lecture-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/25/lecture-5/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Agenda  Review good programming practices Review R functions – for/next, if/else, while/loop
 Show some of the functions R has for matrix/vector operations   Good Programming Practices Most analysis will require some amount of programming. As we program, we should strive to create readable and reusable code. The art of creating good code is captured in the broad and opinionated topic of Good Programming Practices. You will devolop your own style, but it would be good to start with some guidance from some experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R functions and logic, good programming practices</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/19/lecture-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/19/lecture-4/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Agenda  Review data munging and creating tidy datasets Introduce good programming practices
 R functions
 for next
 if else while loop   Data wrangling - messy data symptoms  Column headers are values, not variable names. Multiple variables are stored in one column. Variables are stored in both rows and columns. Multiple types of observational units are stored in the same table.
 A single observational unit is stored in multiple tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data wrangling, munging and creating tidy datasets</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/12/lecture-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/12/lecture-3/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Agenda  Review data importing, cleaning and munging data Creating tidy datasets Using the tidyverse In-class tidy’ing   Data wrangling Data wrangling or munging is the process of going from raw to useful data. This can be 60-80% of the time spent on a project. Data Wrangling Cheatsheet Steps may include any or all of the following:
   Step Examples    Import  read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data structures, Reproducible Research, loading, cleaning and munging data in R</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/05/lecture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/09/05/lecture-2/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Agenda  Review the concepts of Reproducible Research
 Review Git
 Importing, cleaning and munging data Summarizing and exploring data Vectors, matrices, and data frames Homework 3   Thoughts/issues from last time/homework Homework
-Swirl – thoughts?
-Git – ok?
-R – any problems? Knitr and LaTeX?
 Reproducible Research | Review This was the scenario:
You had worked 6 months to analyze a data set. Someone else analyzes the data and comes to different conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductions, Reproducible Research, (a little) R, and (a little) Git</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/08/28/lecture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/08/28/lecture-1/</guid>
      <description>Today’s Agenda  Introduce the course Introduce the concepts of Reproducible Research Introduce Git
 Introduce R as the (main) platform for the course Homework 1   Course Learning Objectives  R programming Reproducible research concepts Good programming practices
 Data cleaning and munging Git fundamentals Markdown Python basics   Tentative Course Lecture Schedule https://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/schedule/
 Passing the course Q. How do you pass the course??
A. Do the homework AND participate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample homework</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/07/12/sample-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/2019/07/12/sample-homework/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This is a sample of how I would like the homework to look when turned in.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Docker -- Work in progress!!</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/docker-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/docker-config/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to do here!!
OK, decided to ditch the local config. In spite of the fact that Docker is supposed to be platform agnostic, it needs some sort of virtualization layer, so some versions of Windows are a no-go, eg Windows Home Ed. We will use Docker in Docker and use Singularity to launch it.
Let’s talk a little about Docker. Docker, imo, takes us to the extreme end of reproducible research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Conf</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/git-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/git-config/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Note, this is a working document describing how we will use git in this class. Every students local computing platform is different and we will see exceptions. Please do this early and let me know if you have issues and see deviations that should go on this writeup. Basically, we need to have:
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stat 5014 Fall 2019 Schedule</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/schedule/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This is the tentative schedule for the 2019 Fall semester.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stat 5014 Fall 2019 Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Syllabus for STAT 5014, Fall 2019.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submitting homework</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/homework-submit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/homework-submit/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Homework submissions will be accomplished through GitHub. At this point, I am assuming you have worked through the Git Configuration document and successfully added the README file via the command line.&lt;br /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rsettlage.github.io/STAT_5014_Fall_2019/about/</guid>
      <description>This class is STAT 5014. It is a 1 credit P/F class designed to get students up to speed with R and at least aware of other languages. At 1 credit, we do not have time to cover many advanced topics. Generally, I will introduce topics and I will provide lots of reading material for those interested in learning more.
Course material Generally, there will be 3 parts:
 Lecture slides &amp;ndash; html style markdown</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>